So far we've been talking about
目前为止 我们已经讨论了
SVMs in a fairly abstract level.
SVM比较抽象的层面
In this video I'd like to
在这个视频中 我将要
talk about what you actually need
讨论到为了运行或者运用SVM
to do in order to run or to use an SVM.
你实际上所需要的一些东西
The support vector machine algorithm
支持向量机算法
poses a particular optimization problem.
提出了一个特别优化的问题
But as I briefly mentioned in
但是就如在之前的
an earlier video, I really
视频中我简单提到的
do not recommend writing your
我真的不建议你自己写
own software to solve for the parameter's theta yourself.
软件来求解参数θ
So just as today, very
因此由于今天
few of us, or maybe almost essentially
我们中的很少人 或者其实
none of us would think of
没有人考虑过
writing code ourselves to invert a matrix
自己写代码来转换矩阵
or take a square root of a number, and so on.
或求一个数的平方根等
We just, you know, call some library function to do that.
我们只是知道如何去调用库函数来实现这些功能
In the same way, the
同样的
software for solving the SVM
用以解决SVM
optimization problem is very
最优化问题的软件很
complex, and there have
复杂 且已经有
been researchers that have been
研究者做了
doing essentially numerical optimization research for many years.
很多年数值优化了
So you come up with good
因此你提出好的
software libraries and good software
软件库和好的软件
packages to do this.
包来做这样一些事儿
And then strongly recommend just using
然后强烈建议使用
one of the highly optimized software
高优化软件库中的一个
libraries rather than trying to implement something yourself.
而不是尝试自己落实一些数据
And there are lots of good software libraries out there.
有许多好的软件库
The two that I happen to
我正好用得最多的
use the most often are the
两个是
linear SVM but there are really
线性SVM 但是真的有
lots of good software libraries for
很多软件库可以用来
doing this that you know, you can
做这件事儿 你可以
link to many of the
连接许多
major programming languages that you
你可能会用来编写学习算法的
may be using to code up learning algorithm.
主要编程语言
Even though you shouldn't be writing
尽管你不去写
your own SVM optimization software,
你自己的SVM（支持向量机）的优化软件
there are a few things you need to do, though.
但是你也需要做几件事儿
First is to come up
首先是提出
with with some choice of the
参数C的选择
parameter's C. We talked a
我们在之前的视频中
little bit of the bias/variance properties of
讨论过误差/方差在
this in the earlier video.
这方面的性质
Second, you also need to
第二 你也需要
choose the kernel or the
选择内核参数或
similarity function that you want to use.
你想要使用的相似函数
So one choice might
其中一个选择是
be if we decide not to use any kernel.
我们选择不需要任何内核参数
And the idea of no kernel
没有内核参数的理念
is also called a linear kernel.
也叫线性核函数
So if someone says, I use
因此 如果有人说他使用
an SVM with a linear kernel,
了线性核的SVM（支持向量机）
what that means is you know, they use
这就意味这 他使用了
an SVM without using without
不带有
using a kernel and it
核函数的SVM（支持向量机）
was a version of the SVM
这是一个
that just uses theta transpose X, right,
只是用了θTX
that predicts 1 theta 0
预测1 θ0
plus theta 1 X1
+θ1X1
plus so on plus theta
+...+θnXn
N, X N is greater than equals 0.
这个式子大于等于0
This term linear kernel, you
这个内核线性参数
can think of this as you know this
你可以把它想象成
is the version of the SVM
SVM的一个版本
that just gives you a standard linear classifier.
它只是给你一个标准的线性分类器
So that would be one
因此它可以成为一个
reasonable choice for some problems,
解决一些问题的合理选择
and you know, there would be many software
且你知道的 有许多软件
libraries, like linear, was
库 如线性的是
one example, out of many,
其中的一个例子
one example of a software library
一个软件库的例子
that can train an SVM
可以用来训练不带
without using a kernel, also
内核参数的SVM 也
called a linear kernel.
叫线性内核函数
So, why would you want to do this?
那么你为什么想要做这样一件事儿呢？
If you have a large number of
如果你有大量的
features, if N is
特征值 如果N
large, and M the
很大 且M
number of training examples is
训练的样本数
small, then you know
很小 那么
you have a huge number of
你有大量的
features that if X, this is
特征值 如果X是
an X is an Rn, Rn +1.
X属于Rn+1
So if you have a
那么如果你已经有
huge number of features already, with
大量的特征值 而只有
a small training set, you know, maybe you
很小的训练数据集 也许你
want to just fit a linear
就只想牛和一个线性
decision boundary and not try
的判定边界 而不会去
to fit a very complicated nonlinear
拟合一个非常复杂的非线性
function, because might not have enough data.
函数 因为没有足够的数据
And you might risk overfitting, if
你可能会过度拟合 如果
you're trying to fit a very complicated function
你试着拟合非常复杂的函数的话
in a very high dimensional feature space,
在一个非常高维的特征空间中
but if your training set sample
但是如果你的训练集样本
is small. So this
很小的话 因此
would be one reasonable setting where
这将是一个合理的设置 在此
you might decide to just
你可以决定
not use a kernel, or
不使用内核参数 或
equivalents to use what's called a linear kernel.
一些被叫做线性内核函数的等价物
A second choice for the kernel that
对于内核函数的第二个选择是
you might make, is this Gaussian
你可以构建 这是一个高斯
kernel, and this is what we had previously.
内核函数 这个是我们之前有的
And if you do this, then the
如果你选择这个 那么
other choice you need to make
你需要做的另外一个选择是
is to choose this parameter sigma squared
选择一个参数σ的平方
when we also talk a little bit about the bias variance tradeoffs
当我们开始讨论一些如何权衡偏差方差的时候
of how, if sigma squared is
如果σ2
large, then you tend
很大 那么你就很有可能
to have a higher bias, lower
会有一个较大的误差 较低
variance classifier, but if
方差的分类器 但是如果
sigma squared is small, then you
σ2很小 那么你
have a higher variance, lower bias classifier.
就会有较大的方差 较低误差的分类器
So when would you choose a Gaussian kernel?
那么什么时候选择高斯内核函数呢？
Well, if your omission
如果你忽略了
of features X, I mean
特征值X 我的意思是
Rn, and if N
Rn 如果N
is small, and, ideally, you know,
值很小 很理想地
if n is large, right,
如果n值很大
so that's if, you know, we have
那么如果我们有
say, a two-dimensional training set,
如一个二维的训练集
like the example I drew earlier.
就像我前面讲到的例子一样
So n is equal to 2, but we have a pretty large training set.
那么n等于2 但是我们有相当大的训练集
So, you know, I've drawn in a
我已经有了一个
fairly large number of training examples,
相当大的训练样本了
then maybe you want to use
那么可能你想用
a kernel to fit a more
一个内核函数去拟合一个更加
complex nonlinear decision boundary,
复杂的非线性的判定边界
and the Gaussian kernel would be a fine way to do this.
那么高斯内核函数是一个不错的选择
I'll say more towards the end
我会在这个视频的后面
of the video, a little bit
部分讲到更多 一些关于
more about when you might choose a
什么时候你可以选择
linear kernel, a Gaussian kernel and so on.
线性内核函数 高斯内核函数等
But if concretely, if you
但是如果具体地你
decide to use a Gaussian
决定用高斯
kernel, then here's what you need to do.
内核函数的话 那么这里就是你需要做的
Depending on what support vector machine
根据你所要用的支持向量机
software package you use, it
软件包 这
may ask you to implement a
可能需要你实现一个
kernel function, or to implement
核函数 或者实现
the similarity function.
相似的函数
So if you're using an
因此 如果你用
octave or MATLAB implementation of
octave或者Matlab来实现
an SVM, it may ask you
支持向量机的话 那么就需要你
to provide a function to
提供一个函数来
compute a particular feature of the kernel.
计算核函数的特征值
So this is really computing f
因此这个是在一个特定值i
subscript i for one
的情况下来
particular value of i, where
计算fi
f here is just a
这里的f只是一个
single real number, so maybe
简单的实数
I should move this better written
也许最好是写成
f(i), but what you
f(i) 但是你所
need to do is to write a kernel
需要做的是写一个核
function that takes this input, you know,
函数 让它把这个作为输入 你知道的
a training example or a
一个训练样本 或者一个
test example whatever it takes
测试样本 不管是什么它
in some vector X and takes
把向量X作为输入
as input one of the
把输入作为一种
landmarks and but
标识 不过
only I've come down X1 and
在这里我只写了X1和
X2 here, because the
X2 因为这些
landmarks are really training examples as well.
标识也是训练样本
But what you
但是你所
need to do is write software that
需要做的是写一个
takes this input, you know, X1, X2
可以将这些X1,X2进行输入的软
and computes this sort
并用它们来计算
of similarity function between them
这个相似函数
and return a real number.
之后返回一个实数
And so what some support vector machine
因此一些支持向量机的
packages do is expect
包所做的是期望
you to provide this kernel function
你能提供一个核函数
that take this input you know, X1, X2 and returns a real number.
能够输入X1, X2 并返回一个实数
And then it will take it from there
从这里开始
and it will automatically generate all the features, and
它将自动地生成所有特征变量
so automatically take X and
自动利用特征变量X
map it to f1,
并用你写的函数对应到f1
f2, down to f(m) using
f2 一直到f(m)
this function that you write, and
并且
generate all the features and
生成所有特征变量
train the support vector machine from there.
并从这儿开始训练支持向量机
But sometimes you do need to
但是有些时候你却一定要
provide this function yourself.
自己提供这个函数
Other if you are using the Gaussian kernel, some SVM implementations will also include the Gaussian kernel
如果你使用高斯核函数 一些SVM的函数实现也会包括高斯核函数
and a
和一
few other kernels as well, since
些其他的核函数 这是因为
the Gaussian kernel is probably the most common kernel.
高斯核函数可能是最常见的核函数
Gaussian and linear kernels are
到目前为止高斯核函数和线性核函数是
really the two most popular kernels by far.
最普遍的核函数
Just one implementational note.
一个实现函数的注意事项
If you have features of very
如果你有大小很不一样
different scales, it is important
的特征变量
to perform feature scaling before
在使用高斯函数之前
using the Gaussian kernel.
将这些特征变量的大小按比例归一化
And here's why.
这就是原因
If you imagine the computing
如果假设你在计算
the norm between X and
X和l之间的标量
l, right, so this term here,
就是这样一个式子
and the numerator term over there.
这里是一个计算的式子
What this is doing, the norm
这个式子所算的就是
between X and l, that's really
X和l之间的标量
saying, you know, let's compute the vector
换句话说，计算一个向量
V, which is equal to
V 这个向量V等于
X minus l. And then
X减l 然后
let's compute the norm does
计算向量V的标量
vector V, which is the
这就是
difference between X. So the
与X不同的地方 因此
norm of V is really
V的标量等于
equal to V1 squared
V1的平方
plus V2 squared plus
加v2的平方加
dot dot dot, plus Vn squared.
点点点 加Vn的平方
Because here X is in
因为这里的X属于
Rn, or Rn
Rn 或者
plus 1, but I'm going to ignore, you know, X0.
Rn+1 但是我容易忽略x0
So, let's pretend X is
因此我们假设X是属于
an Rn, square on
Rn的 在
the left side is what makes this correct.
左边方的平方就是正确的了
So this is equal
因此这部分就等于
to that, right?
那个部分
And so written differently, this is
那么另一种不同的写法就是
going to be X1 minus l1
X1减l1
squared, plus x2
的平方加X2
minus l2 squared, plus
减l2的平方 加
dot dot dot plus Xn minus
点点点 加Xn减
ln squared.
ln的平方
And now if your features
现在如果你的特征向量
take on very different ranges of value.
的值的范围很不一样
So take a housing
就拿房价预测来
prediction, for example, if
举例 如果
your data is some data about houses.
你的数据是一些房价数据
And if X is in the
如果X在
range of thousands of square
成千上万平方英尺的范围内
feet, for the
对于
first feature, X1.
第一个特征变量X1
But if your second feature, X2 is the number of bedrooms.
但是如果你的第二个特征向量X2是卧室的数量
So if this is in the
且如果它在
range of one to five bedrooms, then
一到五个卧室范围内 那么
X1 minus l1 is going to be huge.
X1减l1将会很大
This could be like a thousand squared,
这有可能上千数值的平方
whereas X2 minus l2
然而X2减l2
is going to be much smaller and if
将会变得很小 如果
that's the case, then in this term,
是在这样的情况下的话 那么在这个式子中
those distances will be almost
这些间距将几乎
essentially dominated by the
都是由
sizes of the houses
房子的大小来决定的
and the number of bathrooms would be largely ignored.
从而护绿了卧室的数量
As so as, to avoid this in
为了避免这种情况
order to make a machine work
让机器算法得以
well, do perform future scaling.
很好的实现 就需要进一步地缩放比例
And that will sure that the SVM
这将会保证SVM
gives, you know, comparable amount of attention
能考虑到
to all of your different features,
所有不同的特征变量
and not just to in
而不只是像
this example to size of
例子中的那样
houses were big movement here the features.
房子的大小影响特别大 这就是特征变量
When you try a support vector
当你尝试支持向量机
machines chances are by
时 目前为止你最有
far the two most common
可能用到的两个最常用
kernels you use will
的核函数是
be the linear kernel, meaning no
线性核函数 意思就是
kernel, or the Gaussian kernel that we talked about.
没有核参数的函数 或是我们所讨论到的高斯核函数
And just one note of warning
这里有一个警告
which is that not all similarity
不是所有你可能提出来
functions you might come up
的相似函数
with are valid kernels.
都是有效的核函数
And the Gaussian kernel and the linear
高斯核函数和线性
kernel and other kernels that you
核函数以及其你有时
sometimes others will use, all
可能会用到的核函数 所有的
of them need to satisfy a technical condition.
这些函数都需要满足一个技术条件
It's called Mercer's Theorem and
它叫作默塞尔定理
the reason you need to this
需要满足这个条件的原因是
is because support vector machine
因为支持向量机
algorithms or implementations of the
算法或者
SVM have lots of clever
SVM的实现函数有许多熟练的
numerical optimization tricks.
数值优化技巧
In order to solve for the
为了有效地求解
parameter's theta efficiently and
参数θ
in the original design envisaged,
在最初的设想里
those are decision made to restrict
这些决策都用以
our attention only to kernels
将我们的注意力仅仅限制在
that satisfy this technical condition called Mercer's Theorem.
可以满足默塞尔定理的核函数上
And what that does is, that
这个定理所做的是
makes sure that all of these
确保所有的
SVM packages, all of these SVM
SVM包 所有的SVM
software packages can use the
软件包能够用
large class of optimizations and
大类的优化方法并
get the parameter theta very quickly.
很快得到参数θ
So, what most people end up doing
大多数人最后要做的是
is using either the linear
用线性核函数
or Gaussian kernel, but there
或者高斯核函数 但是
are a few other kernels that also
有几个其他的几个核函数也
satisfy Mercer's theorem and
满足默塞尔定理
that you may run across other
你可能会遇到其他人使用这些核函数
people using, although I personally
然而我个人
end up using other kernels you know, very, very rarely, if at all.
最后是很少很少使用其他核函数
Just to mention some of the other kernels that you may run across.
只是简单提及一下你可能会遇到的其他核函数
One is the polynomial kernel.
一个是多项式核函数
And for that the similarity between
X和l之间的
X and l is
相似值
defined as, there are
定义为 有
a lot of options, you can
很多种选择 你可以
take X transpose l squared.
用X的转置I的平方
So, here's one measure of how similar X and l are.
那么这里就有一个估计X和l相似度的估量
If X and l are very close with
如果X和l相互之间很接近
each other, then the inner product will tend to be large.
那么这个内积就会很大
And so, you know, this is a slightly
这是一个有些
unusual kernel.
不寻常的核函数
That is not used that often, but
它并不那么常用 但是
you may run across some people using it.
你可能会见到有些人使用它
This is one version of a polynomial kernel.
这是一个多项式核函数的变体
Another is X transpose l cubed.
另外一个是X转置I 的立方
These are all examples of the polynomial kernel.
这些是多项式核函数的所有例子
X transpose l plus 1 cubed.
X的转置l加1的立方
X transpose l plus maybe
X的转置加 可以
a number different then one 5
是一个不同的数 然后一个5
and, you know, to the power of 4 and
的4次方
so the polynomial kernel actually has two parameters.
多项式内核函数实际上有两个参数
One is, what number do you add over here?
一个是 你需要在这里加上一个什么样的数字
It could be 0.
可能是0
This is really plus 0 over there, as well as what's the degree of the polynomial over there.
这里就是一个0 这些是多项式的次数
So the degree power and these numbers.
这些数字就是多项式的次数
And the more general form of the
多项式核函数更一般的
polynomial kernel is X
形式是X
transpose l, plus some
转置I 加上一些
constant and then
常数项 然后
to some degree in the
是指数部分
X1 and so both
（在X1上）这两个
of these are parameters for the polynomial kernel.
都是多项式核函数的参数
So the polynomial kernel almost always
多项式核函数几乎总是
or usually performs worse.
或者经常执行的效果都比较差
And the Gaussian kernel does not
高斯核函数用得比不是
use that much, but this is just something that you may run across.
那么多 但是你有可能会碰到
Usually it is used only for
通常它用在
data where X and l
当X和l
are all strictly non negative,
都是严格的非负数时
and so that ensures that these
这样以保证这些
inner products are never negative.
内积值永远不会是负数
And this captures the intuition that
这扑捉到了
X and l are very similar
X和l之间非常相似
to each other, then maybe the inter product between them will be large.
也许它们之间的内积会很大
They have some other properties as well
它们也有其他的一些性质
but people tend not to use it much.
但是人们通常用得不多
And then, depending on what you're
那么 根据你所做的
doing, there are other, sort of more
也有其他一些更加
esoteric kernels as well, that you may come across.
难懂的核函数 这你也有可能会碰到
You know, there's a string kernel, this
有字符串核函数 这个
is sometimes used if your
在你的
input data is text strings or other types of strings.
输入数据是文本字符串或者其他类型的字符串时 有时会用到
There are things like the
还有一些函数 如
chi-square kernel, the histogram intersection kernel, and so on.
卡方核函数 直方相交核函数 等等
There are sort of more esoteric kernels that
有一些难懂的核函数
you can use to measure similarity
这样一些函数你可以用来估量
between different objects.
不同对象之间的相似性
So for example, if you're trying to
例如 如果你在尝试
do some sort of text classification
做一些文本分类的
problem, where the input
问题 这个问题中输入
x is a string then
变量X是一个字符串 然后
maybe we want to find the
我们也许想要通过字符串核函数来找到
similarity between two strings
两个字符串间的相似度
using the string kernel, but I
但是我
personally you know end up very rarely,
个人很少用这个
if at all, using these more esoteric kernels. I
如果真要用的话 就用这些更加难懂的核函数 我
think I might have use the chi-square
认为我可以用卡方
kernel, may be once in
核函数 也许是我
my life and the histogram kernel,
人生唯一一次 和直方核函数
may be once or twice in my life. I've
也许是我人生中的一次或者两次用它 我
actually never used the string kernel myself. But in
实际上从来不用字符串核函数 但是
case you've run across this in other applications. You know, if
以防万一你已经在其他应用中碰到了这样的情况 如果
you do a quick web
你快速搜索网页
search we do a quick Google
用快速的谷歌
search or quick Bing search
搜索或者快速的Bing搜索
you should have found definitions that these are the kernels as well. So
你应该已经发现这些定义也是核函数
just two last details I want to talk about in this video. One in multiclass classification. So, you
我想要在这个视频里讨论的最后两个细节 一个是在多类分类中
have four classes or more generally
你有4个类别或者更一般的是
3 classes output some appropriate
3（K）个类别  输出的是一些在你的多个类别间恰当的
decision bounday between your multiple classes. Most SVM, many SVM
判定边界 大部分的SVM 许多SVM
packages already have built-in
包已经建立了
multiclass classification functionality. So
多类分类的函数了 因此
if your using a pattern like
如果你使用一个类似与这样的一个模式
that, you just use the
你只是用了
both that functionality and that
这样的函数 且
should work fine. Otherwise,
应该会工作得很好 此外
one way to do this
实现这个的一个方式
is to use the one
是用 one-vs
versus all method that we
.all method（一对多） 的方法 这个我们在
talked about when we are developing logistic regression. So
讲解逻辑回归的时候讨论过
what you do is you trade
所以你要做的是训练
kSVM's if you have
kSVM 如果你有
k classes, one to distinguish
k个类别 用以将
each of the classes from the rest.
每个类别从其他的类别中区分开来
And this would give you k parameter
这个会给你K参数的
vectors, so this will
向量 这个会
give you, upi lmpw. theta 1, which
给你θ1 这会
is trying to distinguish class y equals
尝试从所有其他
one from all of
类别中识别出y=1的类别
the other classes, then you
之后你
get the second parameter, vector
得到第二个参数 向量
theta 2, which is what
θ2 这个是
you get when you, you know, have
在把
y equals 2 as the positive class
y=2作为正类别
and all the others as negative class
其他的作为负类别时 得到的
and so on up to
以此类推
a parameter vector theta k,
参数向量θk
which is the parameter vector for
是用于
distinguishing the final class
识别最后一个类别参数向量
key from anything else, and
最后
then lastly, this is exactly
这就与
the same as the one versus
我们在逻辑回归中用到的
all method we have for logistic regression.
一对多（one-vs-all）的方法一样
Where we you just predict the class
在逻辑回归中我们只是
i with the largest theta
用最大的θ转置X来预测类别i
transpose X.  So let's multiclass classification designate.
定义一下多类分类
For the more common cases
对于更为常见的情况
that there is a good
很有
chance that whatever software package
可能不过你使用神马软件包
you use, you know, there will be
都有可能
a reasonable chance that are already
已经建立了
have built in multiclass classification functionality,
多类分类的函数功能
and so you don't need to worry about this result.
因此你不用去当心这种资源
Finally, we developed support vector
最后 我们开展
machines starting off with logistic
以逻辑回归开始的支持向量机
regression and then modifying the cost function a little bit.
然后改造一下代价函数
The last thing we want to do in this video is, just say a little bit about.
最后我想要在这个视频中讨论一点的是
when you will use one of
当你要使用
these two algorithms, so let's
这两个算法中的一个时
say n is the number
假设n是一个
of features and m is the number of training examples.
特征变量 m是一个训练样本
So, when should we use one algorithm versus the other?
那么我们什么时候用哪一个呢？
Well, if n is larger
如果n
relative to your training set
相对于你的训练数据集大小较大的时候
size, so for example,
比如
if you take a business
如果你有一个
with a number of features this is
特征变量的数值 这个数值
much larger than m and this
比m要大很多
might be, for example, if you
这可以是 比如说 如果你
have a text classification problem, where
有一个文本分类的问题 在这里
you know, the dimension of the feature
特征向量的维数
vector is I don't know, maybe, 10 thousand.
我是不知道的 有可能是1万（10千）
And if your training
且如果你的训练
set size is maybe 10
集的大小有可能是10
you know, maybe, up to 1000.
到1000范围内
So, imagine a spam
想象一下垃圾邮件
classification problem, where email
的分类问题 在这个问题中
spam, where you have 10,000
你有 （1万）10,000
features corresponding to 10,000 words
个与10,000（1万）个单词对应的特征向量
but you have, you know, maybe 10
但是你可能有10
training examples or maybe up to 1,000 examples.
训练样本 也可能有多达 1000个训练样本
So if n is large relative to
如果n相对于
m, then what I
m足够大的话 那么我
would usually do is use logistic
通常所做的就是使用逻辑
regression or use it
回归 或者
as the m without a kernel or
用不带核函数的m 或者
use it with a linear kernel.
使用线性核函数
Because, if you have so many
因为 如果你有许多
features with smaller training sets, you know,
特征变量 而有相对较小的训练集
a linear function will probably
线性函数可能会
do fine, and you don't have
工作得很好 而且你也没有
really enough data to
足够的数据
fit a very complicated nonlinear function.
来拟合非常复杂的非线性函数
Now if is n is
现在如果n
small and m is
较小 m
intermediate what I mean
大小适中 我的意思是
by this is n is
在这里n
maybe anywhere from 1 - 1000, 1 would be very small.
可能是1-1000之间的任何数 1会很小
But maybe up to 1000
也许也会到1000个
features and if
变量 如果
the number of training
训练样本的数量
examples is maybe anywhere from
可能是从
10, you know, 10 to maybe up to 10,000 examples.
10 也许是从10到10,000中的任何一个数值
Maybe up to 50,000 examples.
也许多达（5万）50,000个样本
If m is pretty big like maybe 10,000 but not a million.
如果m做够大 如可能是（一万）10,000 但是不是一百万
Right? So if m is an
因此如果m是一个
intermediate size then often
大小合适的数值 那么通常
an SVM with a linear kernel will work well.
线性核函数的SVM会工作得很好
We talked about this early as
这个我们在这之前也讨论过
well, with the one concrete example,
一个具体的例子
this would be if you have
是这样一个例子 如果你有
a two dimensional training set. So, if n
一个二维的训练集 如果n
is equal to 2 where you
等于2 在这里你
have, you know, drawing in a pretty large number of training examples.
可以画相当多的训练样本
So Gaussian kernel will do
高斯核函数可以
a pretty good job separating positive and negative classes.
很好地把正类和负类区分开来
One third setting that's of
第三种有趣的情况是
interest is if n is
如果n很
small but m is large.
小 但是m很大
So if n is you know, again maybe
如果n也是
1 to 1000, could be larger.
1到1000之间的数 可能会更大一点
But if m was, maybe
但是如果m是
50,000 and greater to millions.
（5万）50,000 或者更大 大到上百万
So, 50,000, a 100,000, million, trillion.
（5万） 50,000, （10万）100,000, 百万，万亿
You have very very large training set sizes, right.
你有很大很大的数据训练集
So if this is the case,
如果是这样的情况
then a SVM of the
那么高斯核函数的支持向量机
Gaussian Kernel will be somewhat slow to run.
运行起来就会很慢
Today's SVM packages, if you're
如果你用高斯核函数的话 你就会知道今天的SVM包
using a Gaussian Kernel, tend to struggle a bit.
运行这样的函数会很慢
If you have, you know, maybe 50
如果你有50 千（5万）
thousands okay, but if you
但是你
have a million training examples, maybe
有百万个训练样本 也许
or even a 100,000 with a
甚至是100,000（十万）个
massive value of m. Today's
m值很大的训练样本 今天的
SVM packages are very good,
SVM包会工作得很好
but they can still struggle
但是它们仍然会有
a little bit when you have a
一些慢 当你有
massive, massive trainings that size when using a Gaussian Kernel.
非常非常大的训练集 且用高斯核函数是
So in that case, what I
在这种情况下 我
would usually do is try to just
经常会做的是尝试
manually create have more
手动地创建 拥有更多
features and then use
的特征变量 然后用
logistic regression or an SVM
逻辑回归或者
without the Kernel.
不带核函数的支持向量机
And in case you look at this
如果你看到这张
slide and you see logistic regression
幻灯片 看到了逻辑回归
or SVM without a kernel.
或者不带核函数的支持向量机
In both of these places, I
在这个两个地方
kind of paired them together. There's
我把它们放在一起
a reason for that, is that
是有原因的 原因是
logistic regression and SVM without
逻辑回归和不带核函数的支持向量机
the kernel, those are really pretty
它们都是非常
similar algorithms and, you know, either
相似的算法 不管是
logistic regression or SVM
逻辑回归还是
without a kernel will usually do
不带核函数的SVM通常都会做
pretty similar things and give
相似的事情 并给出
pretty similar performance, but depending
相似的结果 但是根据
on your implementational details, one may be more efficient than the other.
你实现的情况 其中一个可能会比另一个更加有效
But, where one of
但是在其中一个
these algorithms applies, logistic
算法应用的地方 逻辑
regression where SVM without a
回归或不带
kernel, the other one is to likely
核函数的SVM 另一个也很有可能
to work pretty well as well.
很有效
But along with the power of
但是随着
the SVM is when you
SVM的复杂度增加 当你
use different kernels to learn
使用不同的内核函数来学习
complex nonlinear functions.
复杂的非线性函数时
And this regime, you know, when you
这个体系 你知道的 当你
have maybe up to 10,000 examples, maybe up to 50,000.
有多达1万（10,000）的样本时 也可能是5万（50,000）
And your number of features,
你特征变量的数量
this is reasonably large.
这是相当大的
That's a very common regime
那是一个非常常见的体系
and maybe that's a regime
也许在这个体系里
where a support vector machine with a kernel kernel will shine.
不带核函数的支持向量机就会表现得相当突出
You can do things that are much
你可以做比这
harder to do that will need logistic regression.
困难得多需要逻辑回归的事情
And finally, where do neural networks fit in?
最后 神经网络使用于什么时候呢？
Well for all of these
对于所有的这些
problems, for all of
问题 对于所有的
these different regimes, a well
这些不同体系 一个
designed neural network is likely to work well as well.
设计得很好的神经网络也很有可能会非常有效
The one disadvantage, or the one
有一个缺点是 或者说是
reason that might not sometimes use
有时可能不会使用
the neural network is that,
神经网络的原因是
for some of these problems, the
对于许多这样的问题
neural network might be slow to train.
神经网络训练起来可能会特别慢
But if you have a very good
但是如果你有一个非常好的
SVM implementation package, that
SVM实现包 它
could run faster, quite a bit faster than your neural network.
可能会运行得比较快 比神经网络快很多
And, although we didn't show this
尽管我们在此之前没有展示
earlier, it turns out that
但是事实证明
the optimization problem that the
SVM具有的优化问题
SVM has is a convex
是一种凸
optimization problem and so the
优化问题 因此
good SVM optimization software
好的SVM优化软件
packages will always find
包总是会找到
the global minimum or something close to it.
全局最小值 或者接近它的值
And so for the SVM you don't need to worry about local optima.
对于SVM 你不需要担心局部最优
In practice local optima aren't
在实际应用中 局部最优不是
a huge problem for neural networks
神经网络所需要解决的一个重大问题
but they all solve, so this
所以这是
is one less thing to worry about if you're using an SVM.
你在使用SVM的时候不需要太去担心的一个问题
And depending on your problem, the neural
根据你的问题 神经
network may be slower, especially
网络可能会比SVM慢 尤其是
in this sort of regime than the SVM.
在这样一个体系中
In case the guidelines they gave
至于这里给出的参考
here, seem a little bit vague
看上去有些模糊
and if you're looking at some problems, you know,
如果你在考虑一些问题
the guidelines are a bit
这些参考会有一些
vague, I'm still not entirely
模糊 但是我仍然不能完全
sure, should I use this
确定 我是该用这个
algorithm or that algorithm, that's actually okay.
算法还是改用那个算法 这个没有太大关系
When I face a machine learning
当我遇到机器学习
problem, you know, sometimes its actually
问题的时候 有时它确实
just not clear whether that's the
不清楚这是否是
best algorithm to use, but as
最好的算法 但是就如
you saw in the earlier videos, really,
在之前的视频中看到的
you know, the algorithm does
算法确实
matter, but what often matters
很重要 但是经常
even more is things like, how much data do you have.
更加重要的是 你有多少数据
And how skilled are you, how
你有多熟练
good are you at doing error
是否擅长做误差
analysis and debugging learning
分析和排除学习
algorithms, figuring out how
算法 指出如何
to design new features and
设定新的特征变量
figuring out what other features to give you learning algorithms and so on.
和找出其他能决定你学习算法的变量等方面
And often those things will matter
通常这些方面会比
more than what you are
你使用
using logistic regression or an SVM.
逻辑回归还是SVM这方面更加重要
But having said that,
但是 已经说过了
the SVM is still widely
SVM仍然被广泛
perceived as one of
认为是一种
the most powerful learning algorithms, and
最强大的学习算法
there is this regime of when there's
这是一个体系 包含了什么时候
a very effective way to learn complex non linear functions.
一个有效的方法去学习复杂的非线性函数
And so I actually, together with
因此 实际上与
logistic regressions, neural networks, SVM's,
逻辑回归 神经网络 SVM一起
using those to speed
使用这些方法来提高
learning algorithms you're I think
学习算法 我认为
very well positioned to build
你会很好地建立
state of the art you know,
很有技术的状态
machine learning systems for a wide
机器学习系统对于一个宽泛的
region for applications and this
应用领域来说 这是
is another very powerful tool to have in your arsenal.
另一个在你军械库里非常强大的工具
One that is used all
你可以把它应用到
over the place in Silicon Valley,
很多地方 在硅谷
or in industry and in
在工业 在
the Academia, to build many
学术等领域 建立许多
high performance machine learning system.
高性能的机器学习系统